sermo.com 2011-11-23

# Privacy Policy | Sermo.com

## General Statement

This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") discloses the privacy practices for Sermo, Inc. (collectively "Sermo") with regard to your ("You" or "Your") use of the website ([www.sermo.com](http://www.sermo.com/ "www.sermo.com")) (the "Site" or "Sites"). Sermo is committed to Your privacy. Sermo hereby notifies You of the following:

  1. What personally identifiable information is collected from You through this Site.
  2. How the information is used.
  3. How the information may be shared.
  4. How Sermo protects Your information.
  5. How You can seek to correct any inaccuracies in the information.
  6. What Sermo's contact address is for privacy questions.

### 1\. WHAT PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION OF YOURS IS COLLECTED

#### a. Information collection and use

Sermo is the sole owner of the information collected on this Site. We will not sell, share, transfer or rent any personal information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement and the Terms of Use. Sermo collects information from You on the Profile and Registration pages ("Profile pages") on our Site. Sermo reserves the right to collect, disseminate, sell or otherwise disclose non-personal information provided by You.

#### b. Registration

During the collection of information at the Profile pages on the Site, You are required to give your contact information (such as name, address, birth date, physician license information, medical school, institutional affiliations, e-mail address and the like). An e-mail address and birth date is used to confirm Your identity. An email address and birth date is used to confirm Your identity. An email address is also used to contact You about the materials and information on the Site. When the Site requests Your identity, the Site will clearly indicate the purpose of the inquiry before the information is requested. All of your professional information will be authenticated against a third party provider.

#### c. Personal Profile

Once a registered participant, You may provide additional information in Your personal profile describing your credentials, professional experiences, academic background, biography and the like. Your personal profile shall be available for viewing by other registered participants of Sermo and will be considered non-confidential and non-proprietary. Providing additional information in Your personal profile beyond what is required at registration is entirely optional and can be altered or removed by You at any time.

#### d. IP Addresses

Every computer connected to the Internet is given a domain name and a set of numbers that serve as that computer's Internet Protocol or "IP" address. When You request a page from any page within the Site, our Web servers automatically recognize Your domain name and IP address. The domain name and IP address reveal nothing personal about You other than the IP address from which You have accessed the Site.

For the purposes of inviting and introducing third parties to Sermo, You will be given the option to import or otherwise provide email addresses of third parties to Sermo. In so doing, Sermo will not store or disseminate your username or affiliated password nor solicit or spam any third party email addresses so provided.

#### e. Third Party Email Addresses

For the purposes of inviting and introducing third parties to Sermo, You will be given the option to import or otherwise provide email addresses of third parties to Sermo. On so doing, Sermo will not store your username or affiliated password.

#### f. Children's and Minor's Privacy

Sermo strongly encourages parents and guardians to supervise the online activities of their minor children and consider using parental control tools available from online services and software manufacturers to help provide a child-friendly online environment. These tools also can prevent minors from disclosing their name, address, and other personally identifiable information online without parental permission. Although the Site is not intended for use by minors, Sermo respects the privacy of minors who may inadvertently use the Internet.

#### g.Opt Out Procedures

Upon initial communication from Sermo, You may opt-out of receiving further communications from Sermo. To be completely removed from the Sermo mailing list, You may contact [admin@sermo.com](mailto:admin@sermo.com). If You are using an e-mail forwarding service or other similar service please make sure to include the correct e-mail address or addresses.

### 2\. HOW THE INFORMATION IS USED

#### a. Use of Personal Health Information

Sermo does not collect personal health information about individuals. To submit a Ticket, You must provide and submit information to the Sermo server. Within Your uploaded submission, Sermo does not collect or maintain information that would associate this submission with a specific patient or individual.

The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) privacy rule, which took effect on April 14, 2003, allows for the use of de-identified health information so long as identifiers have been "stripped" and a key is not disclosed that would allow the information to be re-identified. Sermo does not possess a key to re-identify patient data.

#### b. Sale of Assets, Merger, Acquisition, Bankruptcy

Information collected from You may be transferred to a third party as a result of a sale or acquisition, merger or bankruptcy involving Sermo.

#### c. Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to Your browser from a Web server and stored on Your computer's hard drive. A cookie cannot read data off Your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Use of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on the Site. Once You close Your browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on the Site, You would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on the Site. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of Your browser. You can reset your Browser to refuse all cookies or allow Your browser to show You when a cookie is being sent. If You reject the cookies on the Site, You may still be able to use the Site, but it shall be limited to certain minimal functionality. The only drawback to this is that the user may be limited in some areas of our Site or limited to certain functions of the Site. Some of our business partners may use cookies on our Site. However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. Sermo and our business partners may use cookies to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that You see on the Site.

#### d. Log Files

Sermo may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Site, track Your movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

### 3\. HOW INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED

#### a. Sharing

Sermo may share aggregated demographic information with Sermo's partners. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. Sermo shall not be liable for the transfer of any personal identification information resulting from loss or distribution of data, the delineation or corruption of storage media, power failures, natural phenomena, riots, acts of vandalism, sabotage, terrorism or any other event beyond Sermo's control.

#### b. Consulting

Sermo may partner with another party to provide specific services. When You sign up for these services, Sermo will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. Per Sermo's contractual arrangements with parties, these parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the explicit purpose of providing these services.

#### c. Spam

Sermo maintains a strict "No-Spam" policy, which means that Sermo does not intend to sell, rent or otherwise give your e-mail address to a third party without Your consent.

#### d. Legal Requests

Sermo cooperates with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties, to enforce laws and third party rights, such as intellectual property rights and laws relating to fraud. Therefore, in response to a verified request by law enforcement or other government officials relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity, or other activity that may expose us or you to legal liability, Sermo can (and You authorize Sermo to) disclose Your personal data and other information about You as Sermo, in its sole discretion, believes necessary or appropriate.

#### e. Forums Including Ticket Titles and Posts, Ticket Votes, Discussion Boards and Blog Comments

When you participate in a [www.sermo.com](http://www.sermo.com/) Forum including, but not limited to, Ticket Titles, Ticket Posts, Ticket Votes, Discussion Boards, and Blog Comments, Your name and IP address may be recorded for purposes of maintaining Your own account within the Forums, and preventing abuses of the Forums (see Forum or online community rules for more details). This information is not used to personally identify You outside the Sermo community. In order to diffuse the information in the Site's Forums to a wider audience, Sermo may, from time to time, collect some of Your postings and group them together to use in a specific publication, print, electronic mailing or other public dissemination. At no point however will Your name or IP address be revealed in any publication. In addition, when Your postings are used in this fashion, they may be edited to fit with the general content of the publication being prepared. It is important to remember that whenever You voluntarily disclose personal information in a forum, through e-mail or elsewhere, that information can be collected and used by others. If Your personal information is accessible to the public, You may receive unsolicited messages form other parties in return. Ultimately, You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of Your personal information. You may participate in any Forums offered through Sermo, but You agree not to post any material the content of which (i) is defamatory, libelous, obscene, indecent, abusive, threatening to others, or in violation of any law; or (ii) infringes the copyright, trademark right, or other intellectual property right of any third party. You will be solely responsible for all content that you post on any Forum of Sermo. You agree to indemnify Sermo and its officers and employees from and against all liabilities, judgments, damages, and costs (including attorney's fees) incurred by any of them which arise out of or are related to the content that you post. Forums are intended only for the personal use of Sermo subscribers, and may not be used for commercial purposes or for organized political activity.

### 4\. HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

#### a. Confidentiality and Security

Sermo takes all necessary precautions to protect Your personal information both online and off-line. When Sermo requests that You enter sensitive information, that information is encrypted using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software or other security protocol, which encrypts the information you input. No administrator at Sermo will have knowledge of Your password. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to log off from Sermo when finished using a shared computer. Sermo also protects Your personal information off-line. Access to Your personal information is limited to employees who Sermo reasonably believes will need that information to provide services to You. However, Sermo is not responsible for the confidentiality, security or distribution of your own personal information by our partners and third parties outside the scope of our agreement with such partners and third parties.

#### b. Links

The Sites, [www.sermo.com](http://www.sermo.com/ "www.sermo.com"), may contain links to other sites. The linked sites are not necessarily under the control of Sermo. Please be aware that Sermo is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. Sermo encourages You to be aware when You leave this Site and to read the privacy policies of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. If You decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to this Site, You do this entirely at Your own risk. Any links to any partner of the Site should be the responsibility of the linking party, and Sermo shall not be responsible for notification of any change in name or location of any information on the Site.

### 5\. CORRECTING INACCURACIES

#### a. Correction/Updating Personal Information

If Your personally identifiable information changes (such as address or payment information), or if You no longer desire to use this Site, You can update Your profile on the Profile pages of the Site. Sermo will endeavor to correct, update or remove Your personal data provided to Sermo.

#### b. Notification of Changes

If Sermo decides to change the Privacy Policy for this Site, Sermo will post those changes on [www.sermo.com](http://www.sermo.com/ "www.sermo.com") so You are always aware of what information Sermo collects, how Sermo uses it, and under what circumstances, if any, Sermo discloses it. If at any point Sermo decides to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, Sermo will notify users by way of an e-mail. If You have provided personally identifiable information before the changes in Sermo's Privacy Policy, You will have a choice as to whether or not Sermo uses Your information in this different manner. If You choose that Sermo not use Your personally identifiable information in accordance with the new privacy policy, Sermo will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was originally collected.

#### c. Site and Service Updates

As necessary, Sermo may send You Site and service announcement updates. You are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the Site. Sermo communicates via e-mail with You to provide requested services and to resolve issues relating to Your accounts.

#### d. Consent to This Policy

The Terms of Use Agreement is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.

### 6\. WHAT IS SERMO'S CONTACT ADDRESS FOR PRIVACY QUESTIONS

Should You have questions about this policy or Sermo's information collection, use and disclosure practices, You may contact us at the address [www.sermo.com/contact](http://www.sermo.com/contact "www.sermo.com/contact") or Sermo, Inc. 215 First Street, Cambridge, MA 02142. We will use reasonable efforts to respond promptly to requests, questions or concerns You may have regarding our use of personal information about You. Except where required by law, Sermo cannot ensure a response to questions or comments regarding topics unrelated to this policy or Sermo's privacy practices.
